Guide to the Fales Manuscript Collection circa 1700-2000 MSS.001
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Letter sized boxes, 47643
  - Kryss, T. L. (Tom L.): MS. Dialogue in Blue [paste up], undated; 49826 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Kuhn, A. K.: autograph of Rutherford B. Hayes, undated; 49825 (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - [L.E.L. (Landon, Letitia Elizabeth): see Landon, Letitia Elizabeth, Box 104], 1690-2000; 49824 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_597b1ba59d996b6819864807c3a3e7e8)
  - LaBelle, Christine: MS. [20 pieces], undated; 49823 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - LaBelle, Christine: MS. Notebook: poems from Alfalfa Wild, The Difference Between, etc., undated; 49822 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Ladd, Henry, undated; 49821 (Box 103, Folder 3a)
  - Lafarge, John, undated; 49820 (Box 103, Folder 3b)
  - La Farge, Oliver (1901-1963), undated; 49819 (Box 103, Folder 3c)
  - Laidlaw, William (1780-1845) (Sir Walter Scott's steward), undated; 49818 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Laing, Alexander K. (1903- ), undated; 49817 (Box 103, Folder 5a)
  - Laing, John W., undated; 49816 (Box 103, Folder 5b)
  - LaMartine, Alphonse Marie-Louise de, undated; 49815 (Box 103, Folder 5c)
  - LaMaziere, Pierre (1879- ), undated; 49814 (Box 103, Folder 6a)
  - Lambert, Hilda Orr, undated; 49813 (Box 103, Folder 6b)
  - Lammon, Joseph (1811-1874), undated; 49812 (Box 103, Folder 6c)
  - [Landon, Letitia Elizabeth: see Box 104], 1690-2000; 49811 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_298007035439a7db1ffab2ce5432fa0b)
  - Landor, Walter Savage, undated; 49810 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Landsdowne, Henry Petty FitzMaurice, 3rd Marquis (1780-1863), undated; 49809 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Landseer, Thomas (1795-1880), undated; 49808 (Box 103, Folder 9a)
  - Lane, John (1854-1920), undated; 49807 (Box 103, Folder 9b)
  - Landon, Letitia Elizabeth (1802-1838): Correspondence I [9 pieces], undated; 49806 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Landon, Letitia Elizabeth (1802-1838): Correspondence II [8 pieces], undated; 49805 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Landon, Letitia Elizabeth (1802-1838): Correspondence III [7 pieces], undated; 49804 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Landon, Letitia Elizabeth (1802-1838): Correspondence IV [6 pieces], undated; 49803 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Landon, Letitia Elizabeth (1802-1838): Correspondence V [6 pieces], undated; 49802 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Landon, Letitia Elizabeth (1802-1838): MS. I, undated; 49801 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Landon, Letitia Elizabeth (1802-1838): MS. II: The Royal Marriage [includes letter to Mr. Shobert], undated; 49800 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Correspondence [1886-1907], 49799 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Correspondence [1908-1910; undated], 49798 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Correspondence [undated], 49797 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Correspondence [undated], 49796 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Correspondence [undated], 49795 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Correspondence [undated], 49794 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Correspondence [undated], 49793 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Correspondence [undated], 49792 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Bound Volume of Correspondence, undated; 49791 (Box 105, Folder 8b)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Bound Volume of Correspondence, undated; 49790 (Box 105, Folder 8c)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): MS., undated; 49789 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Lang, Andrew (1844-1912): Times Obituary, July 22, 1912, 49788 (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - Lang, Anton, undated; 49787 (Box 106, Folder 1a)
  - Lanier, Henry Wysham (1875- ), undated; 49786 (Box 106, Folder 1b)
  - Lanier, Sidney (1842-1881), undated; 49785 (Box 106, Folder 1c)
  - Larcom, Lucy (1824-1893), undated; 49784 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Lardner, Ring (1885-1933), undated; 49783 (Box 106, Folder 3a)
  - Lasker, Emanuel (1868-1941), undated; 49782 (Box 106, Folder 3b)
  - Laski, Harold J., undated; 49781 (Box 106, Folder 3c)
  - Laski, Mary L., undated; 49780 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Lathrop, George Parsons (1851-1898), undated; 49779 (Box 106, Folder 5a)
  - Lathrop, Rose Hawthorne (1851-1926), undated; 49778 (Box 106, Folder 5b)
  - [not assigned], 1690-2000; 49777 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Latimer, Elizabeth Wormeley (1822-1904), undated; 49776 (Box 106, Folder 7a)
  - Lavater, Johann Kasper (1741-180?), undated; 49775 (Box 106, Folder 7b)
  - Laver, James (1899- ), undated; 49774 (Box 106, Folder 7c)
  - Lawless, Hon. Emily (1845-1913), undated; 49773 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Lawrence, Lady Anne: 1 A.L.s. Sept 1939? re Sir Alexander Lawrence's death; 1 Miscellaneous, undated; 49772 (Box 106, Folder 7e)
  - Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert) (1885-1930): MS. Psychoanalysis and the Unconsious [with autograph corrections], undated; 49771 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert) (1885-1930): Miscellaneous: Dust Jacket to F. Carter's; D. H. Lawrence and the Body Mystical; London Archer, 1932; 49770 (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - Lawrence, Harry, undated; 49769 (Box 106, Folder 10a)
  - Lawrence, Samuel, undated; 49768 (Box 106, Folder 10b)
  - Lawrence, Thomas Edward (1888-1935), undated; 49767 (Box 106, Folder 10c)
  - Layard, Austen Henry, Sir (1817-1894), undated; 49766 (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Lea, Henry Charles (1825-1909), undated; 49765 (Box 106, Folder 11a)
  - Leacock, Stephen (1869-1944), undated; 49764 (Box 106, Folder 11b)
  - Leadbeaten, Mary Shakleton (1758-1826), undated; 49763 (Box 106, Folder 12a)
  - Lean, Florence (Marryat) Church (1837-1899), undated; 49762 (Box 106, Folder 12b)
  - Lecocq, Charles A (1832- ), undated; 49761 (Box 106, Folder 12c)
  - Lee, Mrs.: Mat. The Night Alarm, undated; 49760 (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - Lee, Mrs. Hannah Farnham (Sawyer) (1780-1865), undated; 49759 (Box 106, Folder 14a)
  - Lee, Laurie, undated; 49758 (Box 106, Folder 14b)
  - Lee, Sidney, Sir (1859-1926), undated; 49757 (Box 106, Folder 14c)
  - Leech, John (1817-1864): Letters and Drawings, undated; 49756 (Box 106, Folder 15)
  - Leech, John (1817-1864), undated; 49755 (Box 106, Folder 16)
  - Leed, H. E., Rev., undated; 49754 (Box 106, Folder 17)
  - LeFanu, Joseph Sheridan (1814-1873), undated; 49753 (Box 106, Folder 18)
  - Lefranc, A., undated; 49752 (Box 106, Folder 19)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Le Gallienne, Eva, undated; 49751 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Le Gallienne, Gwendolyn, undated; 49750 (Box 107, Folder 2a)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Le Gallienne, Hesper, undated; 49749 (Box 107, Folder 2b)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Correspondence to A - K, undated; 49748 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Correspondence to Bennett, Arthur [Booklovers' Club], undated; 49747 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Correspondence to Griffith, William, undated; 49746 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Correspondence to L, undated; 49745 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Correspondence Printed; Marriage and Death Notice [Mildred Le Gallienne]; Miscellaneous, undated; 49744 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Correspondence to M - Z; unidentified, undated; 49743 (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Correspondence [unidentified], undated; 49742 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Correspondence to R.L.G., undated; 49741 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. Album Dedications to R.L.G., undated; 49740 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. The Book-Bills of Narcissus, undated; 49739 (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. A Borrowed Sovereign; Cyril Leicester; Dear Dead Women, undated; 49738 (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. Do You Ever Get Tired Running the Train, undated; 49737 (Box 107, Folder 14)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. The Eclipse of God, undated; 49736 (Box 107, Folder 15)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. English Poems, undated; 49735 (Box 107, Folder 16)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. English Poems [printed], undated; 49734 (Box 107, Folder 17)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. The First Church of the Restoration, American, undated; 49733 (Box 107, Folder 18)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. The Gentleman Martyrs, undated; 49732 (Box 107, Folder 19)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. George Meredith, Some Characteristics, undated; 49731 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. How to Read Poetry; The Land of Children Unforgot; The Land of Lost Faces, undated; 49730 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. The Laurel of Gossip; The Lord Christ Came to Notre Dame; The Meander of Broken Hearts; Romance of the Map of America; The Shadow of the Rose [see also Legal Size], undated; 49729 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. The Wandering Home; Omni-Bussing; The Case of the Plain Man, undated; 49728 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. 31 Mats., undated; 49727 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. Miscellaneous, undated; 49726 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. Miscellaneous and Fragments, undated; 49725 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): MS. Publications, Essays, Etc., undated; 49724 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard (1866-1947): Minutes of the Book Lovers' Club [bound notebook], undated; 49723 (Box 108, Folder 8a)
  - MSS: A Copy of Verses; My Ladies' Sonnets; Signor Benoni's Violin Playing; Travels in England; Proofs: Quest for the Golden Boy, undated; 49722 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Lehmann, Rosamund (1903- ), undated; 49721 (Box 110, Folder 1a)
  - Leigh, Augusta (Byron), undated; 49720 (Box 110, Folder 1b)
  - Leighton, Clara Veronica Hope (1900- ), undated; 49719 (Box 110, Folder 2a)
  - Leighton, Frederick, Lord (1830-1896), undated; 49718 (Box 110, Folder 2b)
  - Lejmska, Ethel, undated; 49717 (Box 110, Folder 2c)
  - Leland, Charles G. (1824-1903), undated; 49716 (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Lemon, Mark (1809-1870), undated; 49715 (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Lennox, Charles (1735-1806): 1 A.L.s., undated; 49714 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Lenski, Lois, undated; 49713 (Box 110, Folder 5a)
  - Leon, Charles, undated; 49712 (Box 110, Folder 5b)
  - Leontief, Estelle, undated; 49711 (Box 110, Folder 5c)
  - LeQueux, William (1864-1927), undated; 49710 (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Leslie, Frank, undated; 49709 (Box 110, Folder 7a)
  - Leslie, Sir Shane, bart. (1885- ), undated; 49708 (Box 110, Folder 7b)
  - Lettsom, William Nansom (1796-1865), undated; 49707 (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Lever, Charles James (1806-1872), undated; 49706 (Box 110, Folder 9a)
  - Lever, Samuel, undated; 49705 (Box 110, Folder 9b)
  - Leverson, Ada, undated; 49704 (Box 110, Folder 10a)
  - Leverson, Ernest W., undated; 49703 (Box 110, Folder 10b)
  - [Levertov, Denise: see Box 111], 1690-2000; 49702 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_f1526a76343e65a8ae79d6956b1f61db)
  - Levin, Meyer: [see also Box 112 for MS. The Fanatic], undated; 49701 (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - Lewes, George Henry (1817-1878), undated; 49700 (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Lewis, Agnes (Smith) (1843-1926), undated; 49699 (Box 110, Folder 13a)
  - Lewis, Alfred H. (1857-1914), undated; 49698 (Box 110, Folder 13b)
  - Lewis, Clive Staples (1898- ), undated; 49697 (Box 110, Folder 13c)
  - [Lewis, Harry: see Box 113], 1690-2000; 49696 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_f113b9536335f21ca7dddec8a51c889e)
  - Lewis, John Frederick: MS. Imported Brass, undated; 49695 (Box 110, Folder 14)
  - Lewis, Sinclair: Correspondence [1907-1934] [see also Legal Size for Proofs of Four Days on the Webutuck River], 49694 (Box 110, Folder 15)
  - Lewis, Windham, undated; 49693 (Box 110, Folder 16a)
  - Liddell Hart, Basil Henry, undated; 49692 (Box 110, Folder 16b)
  - Liddon, Henry P. (1829-1890), undated; 49691 (Box 110, Folder 16c)
  - Lieber, Francis (1800-1872), undated; 49690 (Box 110, Folder 16)
  - Lindley, Jay, undated; 49689 (Box 110, Folder 17a)
  - Lindsay, A. D., undated; 49688 (Box 110, Folder 17b)
  - Lindsay, Jack, undated; 49687 (Box 110, Folder 17c)
  - Lingard, John (1771-1851), undated; 49686 (Box 110, Folder 17)
  - Linklater, Eric (1899- ), undated; 49685 (Box 110, Folder 17e)
  - Linklater, Eric (1899- ): Notebook [MS. A Year of Space], undated; 49684 (Box 110, Folder 18)
  - Linton, Elizabeth Lynn (1822-1898), undated; 49683 (Box 110, Folder 19)
  - Lion, Leon M., undated; 49682 (Box 110, Folder 20a)
  - [Lionni, Paolo: see Box 114], 1690-2000; 49681 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_83194f407aea18e9cdef3badb33ed7d1)
  - Lippincott, Sara Jane (Clarke) (1823-1904) (Grace Greenwood, pseud.), undated; 49680 (Box 110, Folder 20b)
  - Lippman, Walter (1889- ), undated; 49679 (Box 110, Folder 20c)
  - Little, W.J. Knox, undated; 49678 (Box 110, Folder 21a)
  - Liverpool, Charles Jenkinson, 1st Earl (1727-1808), undated; 49677 (Box 110, Folder 21b)
  - Liverpool, Robert Banks Jenkinson, 2d Earl (1770-1828), undated; 49676 (Box 110, Folder 21c)
  - Llewellyn, R. A., undated; 49675 (Box 110, Folder 21)
  - Levertov, Denise: [Photocopies] [Originals in Caterpillar Archives], undated; 49674 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Levertov, Denise: Love; Origin; Miscellaneous [Photocopies] [Original in specific archives], undated; 49673 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Levin, Meyer: MS. The Fanatic, undated; 49672 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 1: from Allen, Donald; Antin, David, undated; 49671 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 2: from Banks, Russell, undated; 49670 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 3: from Berge´, Carol; Corman, Cid; Creeley, Robert, undated; 49669 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 4: from Enslin, Theodore, 1965-1966; 49668 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 5: from Enslin, Theodore, 1967-1971; 49667 (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 6: from Eshleman, Clayton [see also Angel Hair and Legal Folders: Spurious Poem; Music Recessional], undated; 49666 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 7: from Finlay, Ian Hamilton; Fraser, Kathleen, undated; 49665 (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 8: from Ginsberg, Allen [MS. Fragment from The Fall of America], undated; 49664 (Box 113, Folder 8)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 9: from Greene, Jonathan, undated; 49663 (Box 113, Folder 9)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 10: from Grossinger, Richard and Lindy Hough, undated; 49662 (Box 113, Folder 10)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 11: from Hollo, Anselm, undated; 49661 (Box 113, Folder 11)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 12: from Ignatow, David; Kelly, Robert; Kraf, Elaine; LaBelle, Christine; Locke, Duane, undated; 49660 (Box 113, Folder 12)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 13: from Lowenfells, Walter; Lowinshon, Ronald; Marshall, Jack, undated; 49659 (Box 113, Folder 13)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 14: from McClure, Michael; MacLow, Jackson, undated; 49658 (Box 113, Folder 14)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 15: from Oppenheimer, Joel; Ossman, David, undated; 49657 (Box 113, Folder 15)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 16: from Randall, Margaret [see also El Corno], undated; 49656 (Box 113, Folder 16)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 17: from Schwerner, Arnold; Sinclair, John, undated; 49655 (Box 113, Folder 17)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence 18: from Vas Dias, Robert [1 A.L.s.]; Wakosky, Diane; Zukovsky, Louis [10 pcs.], undated; 49654 (Box 113, Folder 18)
  - Lewis, Harry: H.L., Ed. [and Wakoski, Diane]: MS. Software, undated; 49653 (Box 113, Folder 19)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]: Checklist, undated; 49652 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]: Correspondence MS. A - B, undated; 49651 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]: Correspondence MS. C - D, undated; 49650 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]: Correspondence MS. E - F, undated; 49649 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]: Correspondence MS. G, undated; 49648 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]: Correspondence MS. H - K, undated; 49647 (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]: Correspondence MS. L - N, undated; 49646 (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]: Correspondence MS. R - T, undated; 49645 (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]: Correspondence MS. W, undated; 49644 (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]:, undated; 49643 (Box 114, Folder 10)
  - Lionni, Paolo (1938- ): [East Village School]: Pictorial, Robert Branaman, undated; 49642 (Box 114, Folder 11)
  - Locke, D.R., undated; 49641 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Locke, Duane: 1 A.L.s.; MS. From the Bottom of the Sea, undated; 49640 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Locke, William John (1863-1930): Correspondence, undated; 49639 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Locke, William John (1863-1930): Miscellaneous [see also Legal Size], undated; 49638 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Locke, William John (1863-1930), undated; 49637 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Locker-Lampson, Frederick (1821-1865), undated; 49636 (Box 115, Folder 6a)
  - Lockhart, Charlotte Sophia (Scott) (1799-1837) (wife of John, daughter of Sir Walter), undated; 49635 (Box 115, Folder 6b)
  - Lockhart, John Gibson (1794-1854), undated; 49634 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot (1850-1924), undated; 49633 (Box 115, Folder 8a)
  - Lodge, Oliver Joseph, Sir (1851-1940), undated; 49632 (Box 115, Folder 8b)
  - Logan, Stanley, undated; 49631 (Box 115, Folder 9)
  - Lomax, John Avery (1872-1948), undated; 49630 (Box 115, Folder 10a)
  - Londesborough, undated; 49629 (Box 115, Folder 10b)
  - London, Charmian Kittredge, undated; 49628 (Box 115, Folder 11)
  - London, Jack: Correspondence, undated; 49627 (Box 115, Folder 12)
  - London, Jack: Pictorial; Miscellaneous, undated; 49626 (Box 115, Folder 13)
  - London Letter, undated; 49625 (Box 115, Folder 14)
  - Long, John Luther (1861-1927), undated; 49624 (Box 115, Folder 15a)
  - Longfellow, Alice M., undated; 49623 (Box 115, Folder 15b)
  - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth (1807-1882): Correspondence [1837-1870], 49622 (Box 115, Folder 16)
  - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth (1807-1882): Correspondence [1872-1882], 49621 (Box 115, Folder 17)
  - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth (1807-1882): Mats and Miscellaneous, undated; 49620 (Box 115, Folder 18)
  - Longfellow, Samuel (1819-1892), undated; 49619 (Box 115, Folder 19)
  - Longman, Charles James (1852-1934), undated; 49618 (Box 115, Folder 20a)
  - Longworth, Maria The´rese (1832-1881), undated; 49617 (Box 115, Folder 20b)
  - Lonsdale, William [see also Legal Size], undated; 49616 (Box 115, Folder 21)
  - Loos, Anita, undated; 49615 (Box 115, Folder 22)
  - Lord, Eleazar (1788-1871): von Lennep, E.J. 2 A.L.s.; McCombs, Nelson (Asst Librarian, N.Y.U.), undated; 49614 (Box 115, Folder 23)
  - Lorenz, Lincoln, undated; 49613 (Box 115, Folder 24a)
  - Lorimer, Louise, undated; 49612 (Box 115, Folder 24b)
  - Lossing, John Benson, undated; 49611 (Box 115, Folder 24c)
  - Lothrop, Harriett Mulford Stone (1844-1924) (Margaret Sidney, pseud.), undated; 49610 (Box 115, Folder 25a)
  - Lovelace, Augusta Ada (Byron) (1815-1852), undated; 49609 (Box 115, Folder 25b)
  - Lover, Samuel (1797-1868): Correspondence, undated; 49608 (Box 115, Folder 26)
  - Lover, Samuel (1797-1868): Mats.; Pictorial; etc. [see also Oversize], undated; 49607 (Box 115, Folder 27)
  - Low, Sydney James M., Sir (1857-1932), undated; 49606 (Box 115, Folder 28a)
  - Lowell, Amy (1874-1925), undated; 49605 (Box 115, Folder 28b)
  - Lowell, James Russell (1819-1891): Correspondence, undated; 49604 (Box 115, Folder 29)
  - Lowell, James Russell (1819-1891): Mats. and Pictorial, undated; 49603 (Box 115, Folder 30)
  - Lowell, Maria, undated; 49602 (Box 115, Folder 31a)
  - Lowell, Percival (1815-1916), undated; 49601 (Box 115, Folder 31b)
  - Lowell, Rebecca R. (1809-1872), undated; 49600 (Box 115, Folder 31c)
  - Lowell, Robert Trail Spence (1816- ), undated; 49599 (Box 115, Folder 31)
  - Lowes, John Livingston (1867-1945), undated; 49598 (Box 115, Folder 32)
  - Loy, Minna: MS. Joyce's Ulysses, undated; 49597 (Box 115, Folder 33)
  - Lucas, E. V. (Edward Verrall) (1868-1938): Correspondence [1903-1938], 49596 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Lucas, E. V. (Edward Verrall) (1868-1938): Correspondence [undated], 49595 (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - Lucas, E. V. (Edward Verrall) (1868-1938): MS. Lamb; The Sparrow; Whistler; Stonehenge, undated; 49594 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Lucas, Frank Lawrence (1894- ), undated; 49593 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Luhan, Mable (Ganson) Dodge (1879- ), undated; 49592 (Box 116, Folder 5a)
  - Lunt, George (1803-1885), undated; 49591 (Box 116, Folder 5b)
  - Lyndhurst, Lord, undated; 49590 (Box 116, Folder 6a)
  - Lynn, Neville, undated; 49589 (Box 116, Folder 6b)
  - Lyon, Mary (1787-1849), undated; 49588 (Box 116, Folder 6c)
  - Lysons, Daniel (1762-1834), undated; 49587 (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - Lyttelton, Elizabeth Rich (baroness) (d. 1795): Commonplace Book, undated; 49586 (Box 116, Folder 7)
  - Lyttelton, Elizabeth Rich (baroness) (d. 1795): Commonplace Book [Material with], undated; 49585 (Box 116, Folder 8)
  - Lytton, Edith Villiers Bulwer Lytton, Countess of (1841-1936), undated; 49584 (Box 116, Folder 9)
  - Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron (1803-1873) (Edward George Earle): Correspondence [1830-1833], 49583 (Box 116, Folder 10)
  - Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron (1803-1873) (Edward George Earle): Correspondence [1834-1872], 49582 (Box 116, Folder 11)
  - Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron (1803-1873) (Edward George Earle): Correspondence [undated], 49581 (Box 116, Folder 12)
  - Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron (1803-1873) (Edward George Earle): Copies of letters, undated; 49580 (Box 116, Folder 13)
  - Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron (1803-1873) (Edward George Earle): Miscellaneous [see also Legal Size], undated; 49579 (Box 116, Folder 14)
  - Lytton, Edward Robert Bulwer Lytton, Earl (1831-1891) (Owen Meredith, pseud.): Correspondence [1873-1887], 49578 (Box 116, Folder 15)
  - Lytton, Rosina Bulwer Lytton, Baroness (nee´ Rosina Doyle Wheeler) (1802-1882), undated; 49577 (Box 116, Folder 16)
  - Lytton, Victor Alexander George Robert Bulwer-Lytton, 2nd Earl of (1876-1947), undated; 49576 (Box 116, Folder 17)
  - Lytton: Family Pictorial, undated; 49575 (Box 116, Folder 18)
  - MacAdams, Lewis: Correspondence, undated; 49574 (Box 116.3, Folder 1)
  - MacAdams, Lewis: MS. The Poetry Room, undated; 49573 (Box 116.3, Folder 2)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, undated; 49572 (Box 116.3, Folder 3)
  - Macauley, Rose, undated; 49571 (Box 116.3, Folder 4a)
  - Macauley, Thomas Bobington (1800-1859), undated; 49570 (Box 116.3, Folder 4b)
  - McCabe, J., undated; 49569 (Box 116.3, Folder 5a)
  - McCabe, William Gordon (1841-1920), undated; 49568 (Box 116.3, Folder 5b)
  - McCarthy, Eugene, undated; 49567 (Box 116.3, Folder 5c)
  - McCarthy, Justin, undated; 49566 (Box 116.3, Folder 6a)
  - McCarthy, Justin Huntly (1860-1936), undated; 49565 (Box 116.3, Folder 6b)
  - McCashie, Harry B., undated; 49564 (Box 116.3, Folder 7a)
  - McClelland, Mary Green May (1853-1895), undated; 49563 (Box 116.3, Folder 7b)
  - [McCloud, Fiona: see Sharp, William, Box 157], 1690-2000; 49562 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_e222642c1c7b66437d4865c107fe22bf)
  - McCormack, John, Count, undated; 49561 (Box 116.3, Folder 7c)